우리 4주 후에
결혼하게 된다는 것 알아?
Do you realize we're
getting married in four weeks?
4주라고, 자기
4주!
Four weeks, baby. Four weeks!
목소리가 점점
커지는 것 알아?
You realize you get louder each week?
할 일이 너무 많아!
자기 서약서 썼어?
There's still so much to do!
Have you written your vows?
나도 그 선전하는
약식 서약서를 살까봐
I figured I'd just buy those.
"Pat, I'd like to buy a vow."
나 결혼문제 가지고
장난 안 하는 거 알지?
You know I've no sense of humor
when it comes to this.
- 맞아, 자기건 썼어?
- 아니, 내 건 머리속에 있어
-Right. Have you written yours yet?
-No, but I know what I'm gonna say.
내 머리속엔 뭐가
들었는지 알아?
Do you happen to know
what I'm gonna say?
해 보자,
어렵지 않을거야
Let's do it now. It won't be hard.
생각하는 걸 써 봐
Say what's in your heart.
모니카 좀 봐, 저 사랑을
내가 어찌 따라가누!
Look at her go. She must
love me more than I love her!
난 뭐가 문제지?
그 말문은 열지 말자
What's wrong with me?
Oh, don't open that door.
The One With The Vows
The One with the Vows
'모니카, 말로는 내 마음을...'
"Monica, there are no words.."
말로는 내 마음을!
이거 사람 죽이네!
There are no words!
This shouldn't be this hard!
넌 경험 있잖아, 로스
네건 뭐였냐?
You've done this before.
What did you say in your vows?
캐롤 때는, 죽을 때까지 다른
여자를 사랑 않겠다고 맹세했는데
With Carol I promised never
to love another woman until I die.
그 여자는 그런 말 없었어
She made no such promise.
난 왜 이러니, 모니카는 그냥
얼마나 열심인지 너희가 봤어야 해
I'm pathetic. Monica knows what
to say, you should have seen her.
무슨 비상이야?
What's the emergency?
도와줘, 서약을 써야 하는데
내가 해 놓은 걸 봐
You have to help me write my vows.
All I have is this.
I like the pretty drawing
of you in the wedding dress.
네가 그려놓은
그 웨딩드레스 예쁘다
-Thank you.
-Except your breasts look small.
네 가슴이 너무 작은 것 빼곤
그건 내 눈이야!
Those are my eyes!
- 이게 내 가슴이구
- 그러시겠지
-Those are my breasts.
-Oh, yeah.
그냥 단순하게 시작해
Why don't you start
with something simple?
'모니카, 널 만난 순간부터
난 사랑에 빠졌어'
"Monica, from the moment I met you
I knew I loved you."
글쎄 그건 좀...
I can't do that.
여러분
챈들러를 소개합니다
Everyone, this is Chandler.
안녕, 난 여동생이에요
Hi, I'm Ross' little sister.
그래
Okay.
좋아, 좋아
이건 어때?
Okay, okay.
Maybe you could start with:
'챈들러, 친구로 지내는
동안에도 속으로는'
"Chandler, even though
we were friends...
'좀 더 친숙한 사이를
원했는지도 몰라'
there was a part of me
that knew I wanted more."
핵폭발로 다 날아가고
지구에 혼자 남은 남자요
All right, there's a nuclear
holocaust. I'm the last man on Earth.
Would you go out with me?
데이트를 받아들이겠소?
거짓말로 써도 될까?
Are we allowed to lie in the vows?
그럼 옛날 얘기는 쓰지마라
Okay, don't talk about those feelings.
Just say something about...
그냥 챈들러한테 배운 걸 써
있잖아 왜...
all the things
he's taught you, like..
아님 네가 가르쳤던 얘기나
Or all the things you taught him.
누구나 기본 성감대는 알지
Everybody knows the erogenous zones.
One, two, three...
자기는, 하나, 둘, 셋
넷, 다섯
four, five, six and seven.
여섯, 그리고 일곱
There are seven?
일곱군데나 돼?
- 이것도야?
- 아주 예민한 곳이지
-That's one?
-Kind of an important one.
거꾸로 보고 있었네
I was looking at it upside down.
그것도 가끔은 괜찮아
You know, sometimes that helps.
좋아, 시작은
약하게, 하나부터
Okay, start out with a little one...
둘, 하나-둘-셋
a two, a one-two-three...
셋, 다섯
a three, a five...
넷, 셋-둘
a four, a three-two...
둘, 둘-넷-여섯
two, a two-four-six.
둘-넷-여섯,
넷, 둘
Two-four-six, four, two...
two, four-seven...
둘, 넷-일곱
다섯-일곱, 여섯-일곱
five-seven, six-seven...
일곱-일곱
seven, seven...
일곱-일곱-일곱...
seven, seven, seven...
일곱!
seven!
그래!
이건 어떠냐?
How about something like:
'모니카, 우리가 함께 한
시간을 돌이켜 보면...'
"Monica, when I look back
over our time together..."
- 그리고?
- 나 보지마
-Yeah?
-I can't do all of it.
나머진 네가 돌이켜 봐야지
Look back over your time together.
어머, 쌍둥이다!
Oh, look, twins!
너무해! 난 하나도 없는데
둘이나 가졌잖아?
No fair! I don't even have one,
how come they get two?
- 갖게 될거야
- 언제?
-You'll get one.
-Yeah, when?
들어봐
When we're 40,
if neither of us are married...
우리가 마흔살이 되도록
싱글이라면 같이 하나 가져보자고
-what do you say we have one?
-Why wouldn't I be married?
마흔에 뭣 땜에 결혼을 해?
오해마, 그냥
가정을 해본 거니까
I just meant hypothetically.
가정? 그럼 난 왜 마흔까지
결혼 안 했어?
Hypothetically,
why won't I be married?
아니, 아니
No, no.
뭐야? 진짜로, 난 결혼하면
안될 이유라도 있나?
What is it? Is there
something unmarriable about me?
응?
Well?
세상에, 낙하산이 아니고
배낭이잖아!
Dear God, this parachute
is a knapsack!
나 오늘 결혼한다!
I'm getting married today!
나 있던 거 알았을까?
Think he knew I was here?
시도는 좋았어
Nice try.
잠깐, 잠깐
Wait, wait, wait.
모니카...
Look, Monica..
- 이거 안 통해
- 통할 걸
-This is not gonna work.
-I bet this'll work.
자긴 멋져! 사랑해
You are so great! I love you.
뭐?
What?
아냐! 자기 멋지다고 하고는
말을 멈췄어
I said you're so great,
and then I stopped talking.
- 날 사랑한댔잖아! 어머나
- 무슨 소리
-You said you love me!
-No, I didn't.
- 그랬잖아
- 안 그랬어
-Yes, you did.
-No, I didn't!
- 자긴 날 사랑해!
- 아냐!
-You love me!
-No, I don't!
그만! 하지마!
Stop it! Stop it!
내 짐을 여기다 풀면
어떻게 되지?
You know, I was thinking,
what if I unpack here?
Then all your stuff would be here.
자기 짐이
여기 있는거지 뭐
그럼...
Well...
내 짐이 여기 있다는 건 뭐지?
What if it was here?
그럼 여길 왔다 갔다
하는 거지 뭐
Then you'd be going back
and forth all the time.
그게 뭐야?
Doesn't make any sense.
좋아
Okay.
What if we live together,
and you understand what I'm saying?
우리가 함께 살고
네가 내 말 뜻을 알아 듣는다면?
깜짝 파티였어야 하는데
We wanted to surprise you.
세상에!
Oh, my God!
챈들러
Chandler...
지금까지 살아 오면서
in all my life...
내가 가장 친한 친구와
I never thought I'd be so lucky...
이렇게 사랑에 빠지는
행운을...
as to fall in love with my best..
My best.. There's a reason
why girls don't do this!
- 여자는 이런 거 안하는 건데!
- 그래, 내가 할게
Okay, okay, okay! I'll do it.
난 내가...
I thought..
기다려 봐
I can do this.
난 내가...
I thought...
무슨 말을 어디서 하는지가
중요하다고 생각했어
that it mattered what I said
or where I said it.
헌데 단 한가지
중요했던 건 자기가...
Then I realized the only thing
that matters is that you..
날 상상했던 것보다 더
행복하게 해 준다는 거야
You make me happier
than I ever thought I could be.
자기가 허락해 준다면
And if you let me...
I'll spend the rest of my life
trying to make you feel the same way.
내 평생을 통해 자기를
똑같이 행복하게 해주고 싶어
모니카?
Monica?
결혼해 줄래?
Will you marry me?
물론
Yes.
들어가도 돼?
돌아가시겠다!
Can we come in?
We're dying out here!
들어와! 들어와!
Come in! Come in!
- 우리 약혼했어!
- 좋았어!
-We're engaged!
-Yes!
-Hi.
-What have you guys been up to?
- 안녕
- 너희들 뭐했니?
챈들러 서약서 쓰는 것
돕다가 쫓겨났어
Helping Chandler write his vows.
He kicked us out.
조이가 말도 안되는 소릴
계속했거든
Joey kept making
inappropriate suggestions.
'모니카, 너의 멋진
엉덩이를 사랑해'가 이상해?
How is "Monica, I love
your sweet ass" inappropriate?
모니카는 어때?
How's Monica doing?
멋진 엉덩일 가져서 다행이네
글 솜씨는 없으니 말야
Lucky she's got a sweet ass.
She's not so good at writing.
4주 후에 걔들이
결혼한다는 게 안 믿어져!
In four weeks
they're gonna be married!
잘 되길 빌어주자고
Let's just hope it works.
열 쌍 중 아홉 쌍은
이혼하니까
Nine out of 10 marriages
end in divorce.
피비, 그렇지 않아
That's not true.
그래, 옛 부인들은
안녕하시지?
You're right. How's the missis?
걔들이 함께 지낸 게
3년이라니...
I can't believe...
-they're together 3 years.
-That long?
그렇게나 오래?
It seems like less
because they hid it from us.
우리한테 감추는 바람에
길게 안 느껴지는 거야
나야, 들어간다
Hey, it's me. Coming in.
오늘은 힘든 날이었거든
I've had a very long, hard day.
- 닭고기 사올건데 먹을래?
- 아니, 닭고기 싫어, 안녕
-I'm getting some chicken. Want some?
-No. Bye, then.
괜찮아? 나가지는 않고
닭고기 먹겠냐고 계속 묻잖아
He wouldn't leave.
He kept asking if I wanted chicken.
닭고기?
Chicken?
나 먹을래
I could eat some chicken.
야, 조이!
Hey, Joe!
닭 세 쪽하고 양배추 샐러드,
그리고 콜라 먹을래
Can I get a three-piece,
coleslaw, beans and a Coke?
다이어트 콜라
Diet Coke.
- 왜 그냥 말하지 않았을까
- 호들갑 떨었던 것도 아닌데
-Why didn't they tell us?
-I know, we were cool about it.
너랑, 너랑?
You? And you?
말하면 안 돼
아무도 몰라
You cannot tell. No one knows.
어떻게? 언제?
How? When?
- 런던에서 그렇게 됐어
- 런던이라구?!
-It happened in London.
-In London?!
아무한테도 말 안 했어
뭐 대사건도 아니구
We didn't want to make
a big deal out of it.
대사건 맞잖아!
But it is a big deal!
- 누구한테 얘기해야돼
- 안 돼!
-I have to tell someone.
-No, no!
- 하면 안 돼
- 제발
-You can't.
-Please!
모두에게 말하기 거북해서 그래
얘기 안 한다고 약속해 줘
We don't want to deal with telling
them. Just promise you won't tell.
알았어!
All right!
빨리 자기랑 있고 싶어
레이첼한테는 세탁하러 간다고 할게
I can't wait to be with you.
I'll tell Rachel I'm doing laundry.
세탁? 그게 내 새 별명인가?
Laundry? Is that my new nickname?
자기 별명은 잘 알잖아
미스터 큰...
You know your nickname, Mr. Big..
저기, 모니카랑 챈들러야
야호, 얘들아, 안녕!
Oh, look, there's Monica and Chandler.
Hey! Hey, you guys! Hey!
챈들러랑 모니카가!
Chandler and Monica!
Oh, my God!
으악, 맙소사!
- 챈들러랑 모니카가!
- 으악, 맙소사!
-Chandler and Monica!
-Oh, my God!
- 내 눈! 내 눈이!
- 피비! 피비!
-Oh, my eyes! My eyes!
-Phoebe! Phoebe!
- 괜찮아, 진정해!
- 아냐! 둘이 하고 있잖아!
-It's okay! It's okay!
-No! They're doing it!
알아! 알아!
I know! I know!
- 넌 알아?
- 그래!
-You know?
-Yes!
And Joey, but Ross doesn't,
so stop screaming!
조이도 알아, 하지만 로스는 몰라
그러니까 꽥꽥대지 마!
-Hey, what's going on?
-Oh, hi!
- 무슨 일 있어?
- 와, 안녕!
What? What?
뭐야? 왜?
네가 이 아파트를 얻을지도
모른다니 너무 흥분돼!
We're excited that you
might get this place!
- 사실 아주 멋지긴 하지
- 꽤 멋있어!
-Actually, it looks really good.
-It looks pretty good!
같이 해! 얼른!
Get in here! Come on!
그럼 네가 아는 줄은 알고
레이첼이 아는 줄은 몰라?
So they don't know
that Rachel knows?
그래, 그런데 누가
뭘 알든 상관없잖아
Yes, but it doesn't matter
who knows what.
이젠 우리 다 안다고
말해줘도 되잖아
Enough of us know.
We can just tell them we know.
거짓말이나 비밀은
드디어 끝이야
The lying and the secrets
will be over.
아니면 안다는 말 안 하고
우리끼리 장난칠 수도 있지
Or, we can not tell them we know
and have a little fun of our own.
그래, 영화 보려면
가야겠다
We better go if we're gonna
catch that movie.
- 안녕
-Bye.
안녕, 챈들러
벌써부터 보고 싶다
Bye, Chandler. I miss you already.
봤어?
묘한 말에다 꼬집는 거?
Did you see
the inappropriate pinching?
사실 봤어
Actually, I did.
이젠 피비가 날
좋아한다는 걸 믿겠어?
So now do you believe
that she's attracted to me?
어머나!
우리 사이에 대해 아는거야!
Oh, my God!
My God, she knows about us!
- 피비가 우리 일을 알아!
- 난 걔들한테 말 안했어
-Phoebe knows about us!
-I didn't tell them.
걔들? 걔들이 누구야?
Them? Who's them?
피비하고 조이
Phoebe and Joey.
Joey!
조이!
And Rachel.
그리고 레이첼
말해주려 했는데
말 못하게 약속시켜서
They made me promise not to tell.
우릴 갖고 놀다니, 자기들이
꽤 약은 줄 아나보지?
They think they are so slick,
messing with us!
하지만 걔들이 안다는 걸
우리가 아는 줄은 모르지
They don't know that we know
that they know.
- 그래서...
- 아하, 그래!
-So...
-Ah, yes!
갖고 놀던 쪽이
놀림 당한다는 거지!
The messers become the messees!
엄마야, 나보고 와서
자기 팔 만져보고 그러래!
My God, he wants me to come
over and feel his biceps!
진짜야?
Are you kidding?
어떻게 모니카에게
그런 짓을...
I can't believe he'd do that to Mo..
조이? 걔네
우리가 아는 줄 아니?
Joey? Do they know that we know?
- 아니
- 조이!
-No.
-Joey!
- 너네 아는 줄 알아
- 그럴 줄 알았어!
-They know you know.
-I knew it!
걔네 둘 정말 안 믿어져!
I cannot believe those two!
우릴 갖고 놀 수 있을 줄 알았나?
우릴 갖고 놀겠다고?
They thought that they could
mess with us? With us?
우리가 아는 걸 걔들이 아는 걸
우리가 아는 줄은 모르지
They don't know that we know
they know we know.
조이, 아무 말도 하지마
Joey, you can't say anything.
하고 싶어도 못 할 거야
Couldn't if I wanted to.
수습이 안 돼!
나보고 로션을 발라달래!
She wants me to put lotion on her!
She's bluffing!
겁주려는 거야!
물러서질 않아
이렇게 했다니까
She's not backing down.
She went like this.
물러서질 않아
로션 가지러 갔어
He's not backing down.
He went to get lotion.
아직도 안 끝났냐?
Aren't you guys done yet?
피비가 빨리 챈들러를 무너뜨려야
다 끝나고 공개하게 되지
The sooner Phoebe breaks Chandler
the sooner this is all over.
- 그건 좋다
- 그래
-I like that.
-Okay.
브래지어 보여줘
브래지어를 무서워 해, 못 풀거든
Okay, show him your bra.
He's afraid of bras. Can't work them.
우와!
단추 하나 안 뜯어졌네
Wow! You didn't rip off
any buttons.
처음 해보는 것도 아닌데
It's not my first time.
나가서 자백할 때까지 꼬셔
You go seduce her until she cracks.
알았어, 잠깐만
Okay, give me a second.
- 여기 청소했어?
- 당연하지
-Did you clean up in here?
-Of course.
어, 가는 거야?
Oh, you're going?
너없인 안 가지, 자기
Not without you, lover.
이건 내 브래지어야
So, this is my bra.
아주 훌륭한데
It's very, very nice.
자, 이리 와
Well, come here.
우리가 섹스를
할 거라니 기뻐
I'm happy we're gonna
have all the sex.
기뻐해야지
난 잘 휘어진다구
You should be. I'm very bendy.
- 이제 내가 키스할 거야
- 내가 먼저 할 걸
-I'm gonna kiss you.
-Not if I kiss you first.
이젠 키스할 일밖에
안 남은 것 같네
There's nothing left
for us to do but kiss.
한다
Here it comes.
우리의 첫키스
Our first kiss.
- 그래, 좋아, 네가 이겼다!
- 아하!
-Okay, okay, okay, fine, you win!
-Ha!
- 너랑 섹스 못 해
- 왜?
-I can't have sex.
-Why not?
- 난 모니카를 사랑하니까
- 너... 뭐?
-I'm in love with Monica.
-You're what?
사랑한다구, 그래 맞아
사랑해! 사랑해!
Love her! That's right, I love her!
I love her!
사랑해, 모니카
I love you, Monica.
나도 사랑해, 챈들러
I love you too, Chandler.
둘이 그것만 하는 줄 알았지
사랑할 줄은 몰랐어
I thought you guys were doing it,
I didn't know you were in love.
이젠 다 끝났네
모두 알잖아
That's it, it's over.
Everybody knows.
- 실은, 로스는 몰라
- 아직은 말하지 않아줬음 좋겠어
-Well, Ross doesn't.
-We'd like it if no one told him yet.
안 돼
No.
무슨 짓이야?
What are you doing?
내 여동생에게서 떨어져!
Get off my sister!
친구들이 결혼하면
뭔가 달라질 거야
Friends getting married,
it's gotta change things.
그렇게까지 달라질까?
Think it'll be different?
어떻게 안 달라져?
곧 애들도 가질 테고
How can it not be?
They're gonna have kids...
다른 애 가진 부부들하고
같이 어울리겠지
and hang out with other couples
who have kids.
어쩌면 도심지를 떠나서
And maybe they'll leave the city...
중형차 매장 근처로
이사갈지 알아?
to be near a Volvo dealership.
모든 게 변하는구나
Things change.
난 걔들이 중형차 매장으로
이사가는 거 싫어
I don't want them
to move to a Volvo dealership.
괜찮을거야, 조이
It'll be okay, Joe.
미안, 난 그냥...
지금 이대로가 좋단 말야
Sorry. I just..
I like things the way they are.
이 발가숭이 아기는 누구야?
Who's this little naked guy?
그 발가숭이 아기는 나야
That naked guy would be me.
이 쬐그만 것 좀 봐
Look at the little thing.
그래
Yes.
그래, 그게 내 거시기다
우리 좀 어른답게 될래?
Yes, fine, that is my penis.
Can we be grownups now?
- 이사람들은 누구야?
- 모르겠는데
-Who are those people?
-Got me.
Oh, that's Nana right there.
가운데 있는 사람
우리 할머니야
-Wow.
-Let's see.
- 와
- 보자
'자바 조스에서 친구들과'
"Me and the gang at Java Joe's."
모니카, 너 할머니 닮았구나
몇 살때 찍으신 사진이니?
Monica, you look like your grandma.
How old was she?
보자, 1939년
Let's see, 1939.
그래, 24, 25세 쯤
Yeah, 24, 25.
재미있는
친구분들로 보이네
Looks like a fun gang.
봐라! 발가벗은
모니카 사진이다
Look, look, look!
I got Monica naked.
나 볼래
Let me see.
아니, 그것도 나야
No, that would be me again.
- 안녕, 얘들아
- 무슨 일 있어?
-Hey, you guys.
-What's going on?
그냥 얘기하고 있었어
Well, we were just talking about...
너희들 결혼이 얼마나
멋진 일인지에 대해서
you guys getting married
and how great it is.
그래, 꼭 원한다면
중형차 사도 좋아
Yeah, you can get a Volvo.
If that's what you really want.
상냥하기도 해라
That's so sweet.
- 우리 서약서 다 썼어
- 읽어도 돼?
-So, we both finished our vows.
-Can we read them?
서로 쓴 것
안 듣기로 한다면
As long as I don't hear his
and he doesn't hear mine.
아, 이 부분 아름답다
Oh, that's beautiful.
웃긴다! 이 부분
Funny one! Good!
모니카,
나랑 결혼해 줄래?
Will you marry me?
뭐? 이해가 안 돼
What? I don't get it.
아, 그래!
Oh, yeah!
- 진짜 웃긴다!
- 챈들러!
-Man, this is hilarious!
-Chandler!
걱정마, 자기 건
더 재밌어 해 줄게
Don't worry, we'll make yours funnier.
그래, 어떤 것 같아?
Okay, what do you think?
- 자식...
- 이런 사랑은 못 느껴봤어
-Dude...
-I have never known love like this.
- 정말 마음에 들어?
- 자식!
-You really like it?
-Dude!
이걸 어떻게 썼어?
How did you write this?
모니카 걸 훔쳐서
이름만 바꿨어
I stole Monica's
and changed the name.
- 이러면 안 돼!
- 먼저 낭독하면 되지!
-You can't do that!
-If he goes first he can!